JESSICA GUETRE

Vancouve, BC | jessguetre@gmail.com

Highly motivated Honour student looking for a challenging position where I can apply my academic and problem-solving skills. Fourth year Engineering Physics student in the Computer Science sub-plan at Queen's University. Familiar with Python, Java, C, C++ and MATLAB.

SUMMARY OF STRENGTHS

Problem-solving: Enjoy adapting to complex situations, troubleshooting, and solving problems.

Proven leadership and management skills: Gained through work, school, and volunteer experience, including course-related software development project in C++, experience leading first responder team, tutoring at university and throughout high school, and leading summer camps.

Company experience: Programmed on a team, practicing both independent and collaborative programming. Familiar with workflow in a company and with source control software (GIT).

EDUCATION

Bachelor of Applied Science, Engineering Physics (Candidate) Queen's University, Kingston, ON 2019-Present

- 3rd year Engineering Physics student, cumulative GPA of 3.86 GPA on a 4.3 scale
- Pursuing Computer Science sub-plan of Engineering Physics
- Dean's Honour List with Distinction for first and second year
- Recipient of the Dean's Award of Excellence
- Relevant courses Fundamentals of Software Development (C++), Introduction to Computing Science II (Java), Fundamentals of Information Structures (C), Digital Systems (VHDL), Computational Methods in Physics (Python), Introduction to Programming (C++ and MATLAB)

RELEVANT WORK EXPERIENCE

Nokia Test Automation Developer Intern

2022

- Developed and enhanced test automation in a Linux-based regression environment using TCL scripting language.
- Troubleshot existing tests and made improvements to ensure consistency on different platforms.
- Ran automated regression tests to ensure that new code did not break existing functionality.
- Developed and executed test plans to test service router functions under scale and stress.

Byte Camp Education Society Lead Program Instructor

2021

- Taught kids how to build an HTML5 game from the ground up, including creating 2D vector art
- Promoted to Lead Program Instructor position in first year with the organization and oversaw returning instructors, despite normal one year experience requirement as Assistant Instructor
- Received positive feedback from campers and parents in weekly experience surveys

"My kids had a great time at Byte Camp (Intro to Coding) with Jessica and Kye. They wanted to go to early and never wanted to leave at the end of class and even asked if they could sign up for more classes. Great balance of time on the computer and outside/play time where they got plenty of exercise. The kids learned a lot and were excited to show us what they created in class." Example Google Review

Queen's University Teaching Assistant

2021

- Taught MNTC 313 Introduction to Programming, a course that teaches fundamental concepts of computer programming in C/C++ and MATLAB
- Hosted weekly tutorials, marked weekly assignments, answered questions in 1 on 1 sessions
- Received enthusiastic feedback from tutorial students at end of term

Burnaby Family Life Summer Camp Leader

2019

- Supervised a group of up to 24 children between the ages of 5 and 12
- Designed crafts, games and fun activities to keep campers entertained and engaged
- Ensured safety of campers during daily park outings, while taking busses and sky trains

Elementary School Tutor

2012-2017

- Accumulated over 400 hours tutoring students from kindergarten to Grade 4
- Taught French reading, writing and oral communication, and Mathematics
- Worked with a student with learning disabilities

RELEVANT VOLUNTEER EXPERIENCE

Queen's Engineering Society Industry Relations Committee

2021-2022

- Planned sustainability and diversity job fair for February 2022
- Connecting with companies to attend the job fair
- Working for resume review service

First Responder Seaquam Secondary School

2018-2019

- Founded and ran school first responder team in Grades 11 and 12
- Volunteered as a school first responder for over 150 hours
- Completed necessary 40-hour first responder course in addition to 16-hour standard first aid
- Created and ran health science club in conjunction with first responders' program

ADDITIONAL EXPERIENCE

- Queen's University Outdoors's Club Trip Leader, 2020-Present
- Queen's University QTFS Event Coordinator, 2020-2021
- Vancouver Youth Parliament Member, 2018-2019
- BC Children's Hospital Navigation Director, 2018-2019
- Northcrest Care Center Volunteer, 2017-2019
- Carla Qualtrough Youth Council Member, 2019
- Hostess and Expo at Brown's Social House, 2018
- British Columbia Youth Parliament Member, 2018
- Richmond Delta Youth Parliament Regional Secretary, 2018
- Hostess and Waitress at Ricky's All-Day Grill, 2017
- Duke of Edinburgh's Bronze, Silver and Gold Awards Recipient, 2016-2019
- Girl Guides of Canada Member, 2005-2016

ADDITIONAL SKILLS

- Fluent in English and French
- Proficient in Word, Excel, Photoshop, InDesign and Inkscape
- Familiar with Java, C, C++, Python and MATLAB